Vivank Sharma

Software Developer

Vivank Sharma

401, Taluka Residency, Ramjaipal Path, Patna, BH 801503

909.775.4801 vivanksharma@ymail.com vivanks.github.io

Skills

Software Engineer with experience in multiple frameworks and develop programs using the latest and most appropriate technology.

Goal Oriented individual possessing a never-ending thirst for learning new things.

Captivated by the power of machine learning, deep learning, and Al. Always inquisitive for knowledge.

Key Skills Include:

- Languages: C++, Java, C, Python
- Data Management: Data Analysis, Data Quality Management
- Database: SQL+, MySQL, Ingres, MongoDB, Firebase
- Application: Visual Studio, Android Studio, XCode, Netbeans
- Operating System: Windows, Unix based OS
- Research: Data Science Research Methods, Data Mining, Survey Creation, Image Processing
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Team Player, Public Speaker
- Frameworks: DJANGO ,Node JS, Flask

Experience

Institution of Engineering and Technology / Software Lead

JULY 2018 - PRESENT, VELLORE

Leading Team Fourth Dimension as a technical sub-branch of IET and handling website and making custom software solutions for automating internal proceedings.

Institution of Engineering and Technology / Core Member

DECEMBER 2017 - APRIL 2018, VELLORE

Core committee member responsible for event coordination and managing the internal proceedings of IET On Campus - VIT.

Volunteering:

Technical United Conference 9th Edition / Manager

MARCH 2019, VELLORE

Manager at Technical United Conference a Model United Nations with technical agendas. Responsible for handling the proceedings of a committee and leading the Chair and IP's of a committee.

Hack Off / Coordinator

DECEMBER 2018, VELLORE

Hack-Off a 24-hour long hackathon conducted by IET ON Campus - VIT where computer programmers collaborate intensively on software projects. Responsible for maintaining and developing a website for registrations and idea submission phase. <u>Visit Website Here</u>

Workshop for Young India NGO / Speaker

OCTOBER 2018, VELLORE

Took a series of workshops at NGO on science and growing technology.

Technical United Conference 8th Edition / Coordinator

MARCH 2018, VELLORE

Coordinator at Technical United Conference a Model United Nations with technical agendas. Was responsible for taking care of Delegates and to make sure the smooth flow of the event.

Education

Vellore Institute of Technology / Bachelor of Technology

JULY 2017 - APRIL 2021, VELLORE

Pursuing Information Technology and have enthusiasm in Data Science

Radiant International School / Higher Secondary

JUNE 2015 - JULY 2017, PATNA

Radiant International School / Secondary

JUNE 2012 - MARCH 2015, PATNA

Awards & Honors

- Finalist at Honeywell automation national-level challenge
- Special recognition for non-invasive glucometer
- Special recognition from TIFAC technology incubator of VIT Vellore
- Speaker at IOT Automation conducted by IET On Campus VIT
- Speaker at Web Development Alpha Series workshop conducted by IET On Campus - VIT
- Speaker at Firebase as Backend workshop conducted by IET On Campus - VIT
- Speaker at IOT Automation conducted by IDA Scudder High School

Certification

- Data Science Professional Certificate by IBM
- Ruby on Rails Web Development by John Hopkins University

Projects

Sentimental Analyzer:

A sentimental analyzer Deep Learning model which analyzes slangs and gives the result on the scale of 0-10 where 0 is most negative and 10 being most positive

• Devanagari-OCR:

 A mode is made which is able to recognize and predict different Hindi character which can be further used to identify and digitalize the whole page or text. The model uses improvised CNN model for prediction

• 7 segment display reader

 Developed a solution using Machine Learning techniques which can analyze the snapshots of a 7 segment display and reads the text from those images and returns the numbers/text for further processing. These images are taken with a webcam/camera which is placed on top of the device.

Falsify

 Falsify, is a fact engine with an amazing web interface which takes input from user and then looks up a given fact all over the internet, reads stories, news articles and recognises if the given fact is a statement of truth or not, later it analyses the statement's integrity and tells you if it's a Truth/Lie.

Technical United Conference website

- A multi-page responsive website with a formal black and white theme for a conference.
- Visit website here for more details

• Team Fourth Dimension website

- A modern responsive single page website with a dark theme considering it is a technical website with a touch of neon green
- Visit website here for more details

Learn-Exe

- An online course website where you can learn from a wide variety of tracks of software development also from where you can view online as well as download course in multiple quality.
- Visit website here for more details

Photoblog

- Photoblog provides a social media app kind of interface and in addition, it can be also used for creating a closed network among your friends and family
- With an amazing UI used google cloud for its backend to make it super fast.